bom.com 2015-12-06

# Privacy | Arena Solutions

Arena Solutions, Inc. (" **Arena Solutions** ") has been awarded TRUSTe’s Privacy Seal, signifying that this Privacy Policy (this " **Privacy Policy** ") and related practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe’s program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through these web sites: http://www.arenasolutions.com and http://app.bom.com and does not cover data that you store on our servers as part of your use of our sites and services. For clarity, although the TRUSTe program is limited as described, this Privacy Policy applies to all information collected and stored on our sites or using our services. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions.

If you have questions or complaints regarding this Privacy Policy or our practices, please contact us at [privacy@arenasolutions.com](mailto:privacy@arenasolutions.com) or via postal mail sent to Arena Solutions, attn: Privacy Officer, 989 E. Hillsdale Blvd, Suite 250 Foster City, CA 94404. If you are not satisfied with our response, you can contact [TRUSTe here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request).

Arena Solutions complies with the U.S. – E.U. Safe Harbor framework and the U.S. - Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Arena Solutions has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Arena Solutions’ certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>

Arena Solutions has created this Privacy Policy to demonstrate our commitment to user and visitor privacy. This Privacy Policy describes our information-gathering and dissemination practices for the Arena Solutions web sites which link to this Privacy Policy (the " **Arena Sites** ") and the services (the " **Services** ") delivered by Arena Solutions to our users through the Arena Sites. Privacy on the Arena Sites and within the Services is of utmost importance to us. By visiting the Arena Sites or using the Services, you are agreeing to the collection and use of information in the manner described below.

## Information Gathered

**Registration and Billing Information:** When a visitor to an Arena Site registers to become a user of the Services or requests more information about the Services, we require that the visitor provide contact information such as their name, email address and company name and, when applicable, billing information such as billing address and credit card number. We may also ask visitors, users, or prospective users of the Services for additional personal information such as title, department name or fax number, or additional company information such as annual revenues, number of employees or industry. Personal information that can identify an individual person is " **PII**."

Users and visitors can opt out of providing this additional information by not entering it when asked. However, failure to provide certain requested information may impact a user’s or a visitor’s ability to access the Arena Sites and Services. 

**Log Data and Activity Tracking:** As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.

We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you, including PII. We combine this information to improve the services we offer you, as well as for marketing, analytics, and site operations purposes. 

**Tracking Technologies:** Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by Arena Solutions and our partners, such as our marketing analytics providers and our online chat provider. These technologies are used to analyze trends, administer the site, track users’ movements around the Arena Sites and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We and our partners create individual and aggregated reports using these technologies.

Arena Solutions uses cookies for user analytics and to save a user’s preferences from one session to the next. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use the Arena Sites and Services, but your ability to use some features or areas of the Arena Sites and Services may be limited.

Arena Solutions and third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on the Arena Sites or to display advertising based upon your web browsing activity, use link state objects (LSOs) such as HTML5 and Flash to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs. To manage Flash LSOs [please click here](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html).

**Invite a Third Party:** If a user elects to invite a third party to review and provide input on data it has entered as part of the Services, then the user will need to provide the name and email address of each such third party. Arena Solutions will automatically send the third party an email inviting him or her to become a user in order to review and provide input on the requesting user’s data. Though we retain this information to determine whether a user accepts the invitation, we will not otherwise use this information unless and until the third party signs up to become a user of the Services.

## Information Use

Arena Solutions uses the information that we collect to set up the Services for users and to improve the Arena Sites. We may also use the information to contact users and visitors to further discuss their interest in the Arena Sites and the Services, or to send users and visitors information regarding Arena Solutions or its partners, such as promotions and events. You may opt out of receiving such information as specified in our **Choice/Opt-out** section below. We may also email to users information regarding updates to the Services of the Arena Sites.

All financial and billing information collected through the Arena Sites is used solely to check the qualifications of prospective users and to bill for the Services. This billing information is not used by Arena Solutions for marketing or promotional purposes. Other third parties, such as content providers, may provide content on the Arena Sites or the Services, but they are not permitted to collect any information, except as provided in this Privacy Policy. To facilitate mailings to our users and visitors, Arena Solutions may provide the necessary mailing information to bonded third-party contractors which perform the mailing on our behalf. 

## Stored Data

Users of the Services will be using the Services to store data. Such data may at times be viewed or accessed by Arena Solutions only: to resolve a problem or support issue, to evaluate or investigate an enhancement for the Arena Sites or Services or a suspected violation of the Terms of Use for the Arena Sites and the Services, or as may be required by law. Users are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality and security of their user registration and password. Except as provided in this Privacy Policy, Arena Solutions will not review, share, distribute, print or reference any data stored by users on the Arena Sites or the Services.

## Sharing of Information

Arena Solutions may share aggregated demographic information with partners and advertisers. The demographic information we provide to partners and advertisers does not include any linked PII. 

Arena Solutions may use a credit card processing company to bill users for Services. This company will not retain, share, store or use PII for any purpose other than as needed to perform such billing.

Arena Solutions also may use third parties to facilitate, evaluate and improve the Service, to store data and to enable Arena Solutions’ marketing activities. This may require the disclosure of PII and other user data to these service providers. In some instances, these service providers may collect information directly from users. In all cases, these service providers’ use of user information will be contractually limited to uses consistent with this Privacy Policy.

Arena Solutions may partner with other parties to provide specific events, materials or services. If a user registers for these events or elects to receive such materials or services, we may share names, other contact information, certain PII and customer data if and as necessary for the third party to provide these events, materials or services. In addition, Arena Solutions may provide the third party such other information as a user provides to Arena Solutions in connection with the specific event, material or service.

From time to time we may provide information about users to Arena Solutions’ subsidiaries and joint ventures in order to provide those users the Services. Each of these entities will comply with the policies described in this Privacy Policy. In addition, if the stock or assets of Arena Solutions, its subsidiaries, its joint ventures or any combination of such are acquired by another entity, some or all of Arena Solutions’ users’ and visitors’ PII, hosted data and other information may be provided to such successor. In such a case, the successor will handle the PII and hosted data in the same manner as provided in this Privacy Policy. Please see our **Notice of Changes** section below.

Arena Solutions may also disclose your personal information: (i) as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process; and (ii) when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request. Other than as expressly described in this Privacy Policy, Arena Solutions will not share, sell or rent a user’s or a visitor’s PII or hosted data with anyone outside of Arena Solutions, without such user’s or visitor’s prior permission or unless ordered by a court of law.

## Blogs/Forums

The Arena Sites offer publicly accessible blogs and community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. You may request removal of any of your posts or entries from our blogs or community forums as specified in our **Choice/Opt-out** section below. Of course, such removal will not affect copies of such posts or entries which may have been viewed or made prior to such removal. So we recommend that you carefully consider any such post or entry prior to submission.

## Testimonials

Arena Solutions displays personal testimonials of satisfied customers on the Arena Sites in addition to other endorsements. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [privacy@arenasolutions.com](mailto:privacy@arenasolutions.com).

## Links to Other Sites

The Arena Sites and the Services contain links to other sites. Arena Solutions is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage Arena Solutions users to be aware when they leave the Arena Sites or the Services and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects information from them. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by the Arena Sites and the Services.

## Targeted Advertising

Arena Solutions partners with a third party to either display advertising on the Arena Sites or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on the Arena Sites and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you do not wish to have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) (or, if located in the European Union, clicking [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.

## Social Media Features

The Arena Sites and Services include social media features, such as a Facebook "Like" button and a Twitter link (" **Social Media Features** "). A Social Media Feature may collect your IP address and which page you are visiting on the Arena Sites, and may set cookies to enable the Social Media Feature to function properly. Social Media Features are either hosted by a third party or hosted on the Arena Sites by Arena Solutions. Your interactions with the Social Media Features are governed by the privacy statements of the web sites providing them.

## Security

No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee absolute security for the Arena Sites or Services. If you have any questions about security on the Arena Sites, you can contact us at [privacy@arenasolutions.com](mailto:privacy@arenasolutions.com).

Arena Solutions takes every precaution to protect our users’ and visitors’ information and data against loss, misuse and alteration. As a cloud service, our success is predicated on the security of that information and data. We use standard industry practices as outlined in our [Security Statement](http://www.arenasolutions.com/security/) to help prevent unauthorized use of, access to or alteration of visitor and user information and hosted data. These practices include the appropriate use of firewalls, SSL encryption, system redundancies, and co-location at a 24/7 secured, controlled environment. 

Arena Solutions personnel with access to information gathered from visitors and users have been advised of the importance of maintaining the confidentiality of such information and of using it only for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.

## Choice/Opt-out

Whenever visitors or users submit requests for more information or services from us, they may opt out of entering certain fields. However, such decision may affect the ability to use portions of the Arena Sites and the Services. If you receive marketing or similar email messages from us and wish to opt out of receiving such messages, then you may simply follow the opt-out procedure specified in such email. If you post a comment on the Arena Solutions blogs or community forums and want your entry removed, email your request to [privacy@arenasolutions.com](mailto:privacy@arenasolutions.com) with "Remove Blog/Forum Entry" in the subject field. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

## Updating Contact Information

We encourage our visitors and users to update and edit their contact information and keep it current. Users can easily correct, delete or update their contact information at any time through the Services and users may request the deletion as well as correction or updating of their contact information by emailing [privacy@arenasolutions.com](mailto:privacy@arenasolutions.com). Requests to access, change, or delete your information will be handled within 15 days.

## Information Retention

We will retain your PII for at least as long as your account or any account with which you are associated is active. Arena Solutions also retains PII in terminated accounts as well as deleted and changed information in our archive in accordance with our data retention policies. In addition, Arena Solutions will retain and may use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, enforce our agreements, and in connection with marketing activities disclosed in this Privacy Policy. 

## Notice of Changes

Arena Solutions may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time. If Arena Solutions is going to use your PII in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify you via email sent to the email address you have provided to us prior to the change becoming effective. You will have a choice as to whether or not we use your PII in this different manner. In addition, if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that do not affect visitor or user PII already stored in our database, we will post a prominent notice on the Arena Sites or in the Services notifying users of the change. In some cases where we post the notice, prior to the change becoming effective we will also email users who have opted to receive communications from us notifying them of such changes in our privacy practices.

## Contact Us

**Last Updated:** on 6/22/2015
